[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
- [creepy giggling]
- [令人毛骨悚然的咯咯笑]
- Hmm.
- 唔。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- SpongeBob! Where are those
patties?
- 海绵宝宝！那些在哪里
肉饼？
- Coming right...down,
Squidward.
- 向右...向下，
章鱼哥。
- What are you talking about,
SpongeBob?
- 你在说什么，
海绵宝宝？
Don't you mean
coming right up?
你不是说
马上就来吗？
- Mmm...
- I don't see what you're--
- 嗯...
-我不明白你是什么--
[sizzling]
Aah!
[嘶嘶声]
啊啊！
- Nice catch, Squidward!
- 钓得好，章鱼哥！
- Thanks...
- 谢谢...
[child crying]
[孩子的哭声]
- Whoo!
- 呼！
[chortling, gibbering]
[咯咯笑，胡言乱语]
- I want my teddy fish!
- 我想要我的泰迪鱼！
Waaaaah!
- Ha ha, all right,
哇啊啊！
- 哈哈，好吧，
don't worry, little boy,
we'll find it!
别担心，小男孩，
我们会找到它的！
This kid lost his toy.
这孩子丢了他的玩具。
SpongeBob, I need you to check
the Lost and Found.
海绵宝宝，我需要你检查一下
失物招领处。
- Ooh! I didn't know
we had a Lost and Found.
- 哦！我不知道
我们有失物招领处。
- I love my teddy fish!
- 我喜欢我的泰迪鱼！
[wailing]
[哀号]
- You better find it quick,
SpongeBob.
- 你最好快点找到它，
海绵宝宝。
Kid's bawlin' is chasing
me customers away.
孩子的哭声正在追逐
我的顾客走了。
Follow me, boy-o!
跟我来，小伙子！
- Waaaaaaah!
- 哇啊啊啊！
[both coughing]
[两人都咳嗽]
- Is there a ladder?
- 有梯子吗？
- Yes.
- 是的。
- Aaaaahhh!
- 啊啊啊！
Aaaaah!
[whomp]
啊啊啊！
[重击]
- Here's the ladder, boy-o!
- Okay, I--
- 这是梯子，小伙子！
- 好吧，我--
[whack]
[重击]
Nice catch!
不错的收获！
- [groaning, grunting]
- [呻吟，咕哝]
[wham]
Ow!
[重击]
噢！
- Now, try not to get bit
by anything poisonous!
- 现在，尽量不要被咬
任何有毒的东西！
- What?
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
- 什么？
- 哦，没什么，没什么。
Good luck!
祝你好运！
- Oh, this must be
the Lost and Found!
- 哦，这一定是
失物招领处！
It's not in here!
它不在这里！
- Try turning on the lights!
- 尝试打开灯！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
[click]
[点击]
- [gasps]
Oh! Whoa!
- [喘气]
哦！哇！
Whoa!
哇！
Wow! Lost umbrellas!
哇！雨伞丢了！
Lost flip flops!
人字拖丢了！
Lost keys! Lost remotes!
钥匙丢了！遥控器丢了！
Oh! A whole, entire shelf of
lost "cool guy" shades!
哦！整整一整个架子
失去了“酷哥”色调！
Now, that's a sight
for more eyes.
现在，这是一个景象
为了更多的眼睛。
[laughs]
[笑]
Oh, no pictures, please.
噢，没有照片，拜托。
Did you get my good side?
[laughs]
你得到我的好处了吗？
[笑]
[giggle echoes]
[咯咯回声]
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
What a funny echo.
多么有趣的回声啊。
Ha...ha.
哈哈。
[giggle echoes]
[咯咯回声]
[gulps]
Hey!
[吞咽]
嘿！
[laughs]
There's bric-a-brac
[笑]
有小摆设
and gee-gaws!
哎呀！
[gasps] I wonder
if there's tchotchkes!
[喘气]我想知道
如果有小玩意的话！
Oh! Oh!
哦！哦！
Tchotchkes!
小摆设！
Lost novelty items!
新奇物品丢失！
Wow!
哇！
I love lost novelty items!
我喜欢丢失的新奇物品！
Ooh!
哦！
[teeth clicking]
Uh-uh-eh-eh-uh--
[牙齿咔嚓]
呃呃呃呃呃呃——
[whoopee cushions farting]
Excuse me!
[呼呼垫放屁]
对不起！
Oh!
哦！
Ah!
啊!
[cushions fart
in rhythm to Latin music]
[坐垫放屁
以拉丁音乐的节奏]
[fart-fart-fart-fart]
*
[放屁放屁放屁]
[fart-fart-fart-fart-fart]
*
[放屁放屁放屁放屁]
[fart-fart-fart]
*
[放屁放屁]
Whaa!
哇！
Aah!
啊啊！
[clucking]
[咯咯笑]
[fart fart-fart-fart fart!]
【放屁放屁放屁！】
[fart fart]
[放屁放屁]
Oh, thank you,
cymbal-clapping sea chimps!
哦，谢谢你，
敲铙钹的海黑猩猩！
What is this?
这是什么？
Looks like Bikini Bottom.
看起来像比基尼泳裤。
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Yee! Eee-eee-eee!
呀！诶诶诶！
Whew!
哇！
[wham]
Whoa!
[重击]
哇！
[distant chuckle]
[远处的笑声]
- Hey, Mr. Krabs,
you know that annoying
- 嘿，蟹老板先生，
你知道那很烦人
crying kid?
[crying in background]
爱哭的孩子？
[背景中哭泣]
He's still crying...
and it's still annoying!
他还在哭……
而且还是很烦人！
- Squidward,
I'm glad you're here.
- 章鱼哥，
我很高兴你在这里。
I think SpongeBob may be lost
in the Lost and Found.
我认为海绵宝宝可能会迷失
在失物招领处。
- And this concerns me how,
exactly?
- 这让我担心，
到底是？
Wait--what?!
等等——什么？！
Aaaaahhhhhh!
- Don't worry.
啊啊啊啊！
- 不用担心。
There's a ladder.
有一个梯子。
[crying continues]
[哭泣继续]
all: [angry muttering]
全体：[愤怒的嘀咕]
- And find that toy...
- 找到那个玩具...
pronto!
很快！
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
Whoa! Are you the people
of the too-small clothes?
哇！你是人民吗
衣服太小了？
- No. We were children,
lost in the Krusty Krab
- 不，我们还是孩子，
迷失在蟹堡王中
over 60 years ago,
60多年前，
and we were never claimed.
我们从未被认领。
- Did you drop a box
on my head?
- 你掉了一个盒子吗
在我头上？
- Of course!
It's how we say hello.
- 当然！
这就是我们打招呼的方式。
- Oh!
- 哦！
Hello!
- [weakly] Hello.
你好！
- [弱弱地] 你好。
[moaning]
[呻吟]
- Oh, no...looks like
I'm lost now too.
- 哦，不……看起来像
我现在也迷路了。
- Don't worry. You are found
and can live with us now.
- 不用担心。你被发现了
现在可以和我们住在一起了。
- How did you survive
down here all this time?
- 你是怎么活下来的
一直在这里？
- People leave
all kinds of things behind.
- 人们离开
各种事情都在后面。
Like gum. And mints.
就像口香糖一样。还有薄荷糖。
They leave lots of mints.
他们留下很多薄荷糖。
- Your breath
is delightfully fresh.
- 你的呼吸
新鲜得令人愉快。
- [claps twice]
Bring on the welcoming feast!
- [鼓掌两次]
来一场迎新盛宴吧！
all: Welcoming feast!
全体：欢迎盛宴！
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[ding]
[叮]
- Dig in!
- 挖进去！
- [crunching, cracking]
Ooh...
- [嘎吱作响，破裂]
哦...
- Hey, little dolly.
You must be getting hungry!
- 嘿，小娃娃。
你一定饿了！
[doll squeaks]
- Oh, hey!
[娃娃吱吱声]
- 哦，嘿！
That's the teddy fish!
这就是泰迪鱼！
My boss, Mr. Krabs,
told me to grab that.
我的老板蟹老板先生
告诉我抓住那个。
Thank you!
- Grr! This?
谢谢你！
- 呃！这？
I found it, so...
finders keepers!
我找到了，所以...
发现者、守护者！
- Finders keepers.
Finders keepers.
- 发现者和守门员。
发现者守门员。
- Huh?
- Yoink!
- 啊？
- 哟克！
Losers weepers!
失败者哭泣！
- He is using our sacred words
against us!
- 他正在使用我们神圣的话语
反对我们！
- That's my teddy fish!
Get him!
- 那是我的泰迪鱼！
抓住他！
- Sorry, but this has to go back
to its rightful owner!
- 抱歉，但这必须回去
归其合法拥有者！
[all gasping,
wheezing, coughing]
[全都气喘吁吁，
气喘、咳嗽]
- Run...like the wind...
- 奔跑吧……像风一样……
- Moron!
I mean, SpongeBoooob?!
- 白痴！
我的意思是，海绵布布？！
I can't believe Old Man Krabs
has held on to all this stuff.
我不敢相信蟹老翁
一直坚持所有这些东西。
Oooh! Kazoos!
噢！卡祖笛！
Why, I had a kazoo
when I was a child...
为什么，我有一支卡祖笛
当我还是个孩子的时候...
Everybody loved it!
每个人都喜欢它！
[playing off-key notes]
[演奏走调音符]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Oh! Ow! My ears!
- 哦！噢！我的耳朵！
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- These are clarinets!!
- 这些是单簧管！
In fact, these are
all my clarinets!
其实这些都是
我所有的单簧管！
Wait a minute--
these weren't lost!
等一下——
这些并没有丢失！
They were all in my locker!
它们都在我的储物柜里！
Mmm...
[panting gets louder]
嗯...
[喘气声变大]
Now what could that possibly--
现在这可能是什么——
Uhhh!
呃！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[clarinets cracking]
[单簧管爆裂声]
*
[groans]
[呻吟]
Typical.
典型的。
- Squidward? SpongeBob?
- 章鱼哥？海绵宝宝？
It's the curse
of the Lost and Found:
这是诅咒
失物招领处：
no one ever gets found.
没有人被发现。
They just stay lost.
他们只是迷路了。
Oh, well, back to work.
哦，好吧，回去工作吧。
- Waaaah!
- The ambiance in this place
- 哇啊啊！
- 这个地方的氛围
stinks!
很臭！
- [gasps] Stinky ambiance?
- [喘气] 气氛很臭？
Oooh, it's a dark time
for the Krusty Krab.
噢，这是一个黑暗的时刻
为蟹堡王。
- Waaaaah!
- 哇啊啊！
- Waaaaaah!
- 哇啊啊啊！
- Oh! Lost toys!
- 哦！玩具丢了！
Aah!
[panting]
啊啊！
[气喘吁吁]
[all wheezing]
- Get him!
[全都气喘吁吁]
- 抓住他！
[thud]
- Uhh!
[砰]
- 呃！
[clinking]
[叮叮当当]
- Whoa--oh!
- 哇 - 哦！
[boom]
[繁荣]
Lost Toilets?
厕所丢了？
- We need more speed!
- 我们需要更快的速度！
[flushes, water rushes]
[冲水，水流]
- [mutters]
- [嘀咕]
- Aah!
- Ohh!
- 啊啊！
- 哦！
- Wha-ooh...
- 哇哦...
[boom]
[繁荣]
- Lost Pets!
- 丢失的宠物！
[gasps, whimpers]
[喘息，呜咽]
- Hyah! Hyah!
- 哈！哈！
Mush! Mush!
糊涂！糊涂！
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
[all whistling cheerfully]
[大家欢快地吹着口哨]
- Lost Mine!
- 我的丢失了！
[thud]
Whaa--
[砰]
哇——
[deep inhale]
[blows]
[深吸气]
[打击]
[old kids groaning]
[老孩子的呻吟声]
- Lost world!
- 失落的世界！
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
- A hatch! Maybe
that's the emergency exit!
- 舱门！也许
那是紧急出口！
Grease trap!?
隔油池！？
[Squidward screaming]
[章鱼哥尖叫]
- [panicked breathing,
whimpering]
- [惊慌的呼吸，
呜咽]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
Lost dead ends?!
迷失了死胡同？！
[whimpering, muttering]
[呜咽，低语]
- Give us the teddy fish!
- 把泰迪鱼给我们！
- Teddy fish!
Teddy fish!
- 泰迪鱼！
泰迪鱼！
- No! This teddy fish belongs
to a poor, sweet child!
- 不！这条泰迪鱼属于
给一个可怜的、可爱的孩子！
Huh?
啊？
Patty grease?
帕蒂油脂？
Oh, no! I haven't cleaned
the grease trap in years!
哦，不！我还没清理过
多年来的油脂捕集器！
both: Oh, no.
- Quick!
两人：哦，不。
- 快的！
Get on each other's
shoulders.
搭上彼此的
肩膀。
At least some of us
will survive.
至少我们中的一些人
会生存下来。
- Aw, come on!
- 噢，来吧！
- Wait!
I have a better idea!
- 等待！
我有一个更好的主意！
[sharp whistle]
[尖锐的口哨声]
[both wailing]
[双双哀嚎]
- No SpongeBob,
no teddy fish,
- 没有海绵宝宝，
没有泰迪鱼，
no customers!
没有顾客！
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
All is lost!
一切都失去了！
[pounding on trap door]
[敲击活板门]
[sniffles]
Who is it?
[抽鼻子]
是谁？
- Tylo!
- Tylo who?
- 泰洛！
- 泰洛是谁？
- [gasps]
- Tylosaurus!
- [喘气]
- 霸王龙！
- SpongeBob!
Thank Neptune you're back, son!
- 海绵宝宝！
感谢海王星，你回来了，儿子！
- Oh, good to be back
Mr. Krabs,
- 哦，很高兴回来
蟹老板先生，
but I'm not the only one.
Look who I found!
但我不是唯一一个。
看看我找到谁了！
- Ack! Get back! Get back!
- 嗯！回来吧！回来吧！
- Ginger? Is that you?
- 姜？那是你吗？
- Mom!
What are you doing here?
- 妈妈！
你在这里做什么？
- We come here every week.
- 我们每周都来这里。
- "We"?
- “我们”？
- Yes.
Myself and your father
- 是的。
我和你父亲
and the other parents
of kids who were lost here.
和其他父母
在这里失踪的孩子们。
Where were you?
当时你在哪里？
- In the Lost and Found!
- 在失物招领处！
- [stutters]
There's a Lost and Found?
- [结结巴巴]
有失物招领处吗？
- Hm. Maybe I should
put up a sign.
- 嗯。也许我应该
竖起一个标志。
[all muttering]
- Aww, all the old people
[大家嘀咕]
- 哇，所有的老人
are hugging.
all: Uhh...ow...ow!
正在拥抱。
全体：呃……呜……呜！
- Dry your tears, little kid.
- 擦干你的眼泪，小孩子。
Look! It's teddy fish!
看！这是泰迪鱼！
- I don't want that anymore!
- 我不想再这样了！
- Huh?
Mmm.
- 啊？
嗯。
- I want this! Whaaa-hooo!
- 我想要这个！哇啊呼！
- Well, I guess
we all learned a lesson
- 嗯，我想
我们都吸取了教训
about being lost
and being found today.
关于迷失
并于今日被发现。
- What's that,
Mr. Krabs?
- 那是什么，
蟹老板？
- I don't know.
- Hey, speaking of lost,
- 我不知道。
- 嘿，说到迷失，
where's Squidward?
章鱼哥在哪里？
- Ahhhhhhh!
[blows off-key note]
- 啊啊啊啊！
[吹走调的音符]
Aaaaahhhhhhhhhh!
啊啊啊啊啊啊！
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]